Finding Aid for Robert M. Wenley pamphlets and reprints, undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert M. Wenley pamphlets and reprints undated
Wenley, Robert M. (Robert Mark), 1861-1929.
DA 2; W476; P186
1 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was gathered from different sources.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert Mark Wenley was professor of philosophy at the University of Michigan.
This is a collection of pamphlets and reprints drawn from different sources and arranged alphabetically.
Subjects:
Philosophy.
- Pamphlets and reprints
  - Academic freedom 1902 (Box 1)
  - Academic originality 1901 (Box 1)
  - The affinity of Plato's "Republic" for modern thought 1905 (Box 1)
  - The Ann Arbor School of Religion 1910 (Box 1)
  - Are they lost years? 1924 (Box 1)
  - The basis of religion -- a fragment 1898 (Box 1)
  - Beati Possidentes 1923 (Box 1)
  - Can we stem the tide? 1907 (Box 1)
  - The changing temper of modern thought 1900 (Box 1)
  - Christianity: The way in 1910 (Box 1)
  - The classics and the elective system 1910 (Box 1)
  - Disce aut discede 1919 (Box 1)
  - Edward Caird 1909 (Box 1)
  - Far away and long ago undated (Box 1)
  - The Gifford lectureships 1899 (Box 1)
  - The halo of a hundred years (February, 1809 to February, 1909) 1909 (Box 1)
  - Henry Carter Adams 1922 (Box 1)
  - Huxley's agnosticism 1925 (Box 1)
  - Immanuel Kant 1924 (Box 1)
  - In quest of progress 1912 (Box 1)
  - John Dalton and his achievement 1910 (Box 1)
  - Kant and theology 1924 (Box 1)
  - Die Klassiker und das Wahlsystem undated (Box 1)
  - The Lit (Box 1)
  - Marian Evans and "George Eliot" 1922 (Box 1)
  - The movement towards "physiological" psychology 1908 (Box 1)
  - The nature of culture studies 1905 (Box 1)
  - Nietzsche--Traffics and discoveries 1921 (Box 1)
  - The old quarrel between poetry and philosophy 1898 (Box 1)
  - The Oxford doctorate of philosophy 1918 (Box 1)
  - The pessimistic element in Goethe 1892 (Box 1)
  - A philosophical, anatomical, and psychological study of Christian Science 1903 (Box 1)
  - Philosophy in American colleges 1897 (Box 1)
  - The pleasures of reading 1911 (Box 1)
  - The present and future of religious thought in Scotland 1897 (Box 1)
  - Reckless tenants 1919 (Box 1)
  - Religions, metaphysics and religion 1893 (Box 1)
  - Rudyard Kipling-poet 1899 (Box 1)
  - Rudyard Kipling-rhapsodist 1899 (Box 1)
  - Science and philosophy 1901 (Box 1)
  - Some light on the British idealistic movement in the nineteenth century undated (Box 1)
  - Speculations concerning conditions accountable for characteristics of British culture which puzzle us in America 1928 (Box 1)
    (Address given to Michigan Authors Association, Detroit)
  - 'Tis sixty years since 1929 (Box 1)
  - Transition or what? 1907 (Box 1)
  - The university extension movement in Scotland 1895 [Article] (Box 1)
  - The university extension movement in Scotland 1895 [Pamphlet] (Box 1)
  - The University in the United States 1907 (Box 1)
  - The University of Michigan in the war 1918 (Box 1)
  - An unrecognized achievement 1899 (Box 1)
  - The valley of decision 1901 (Box 1)
- Book Reviews
  - A Commentary to Kant's "Critique of Pure Reason," 1918 by Norman Kemp Smith. from: The Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Faith and Doubt. Letter to the editor 1913 (Box 1)
  - A History of European Thought in the Nineteenth Century. 1912 by John Theodore Merz. Vol. III. from: Science, 1913 (Box 1)
  - The Kahn Foundation for the Foreign Travel of American Teachers, Reports, Vol. I. Nos. 1 and 2. from: Science, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Kant and His Philosophical Revolution, 1910. by Robert Mark Wenley. from: Selbstanzeigen 1922 (Box 1)
  - Lectures and Essays on Natural Theology and Ethics 1898 by William Wallace. from: The American Journal of Theology (Box 1)
  - Man and the Cosmos, An Introduction to Metaphysics 1922 by Joseph Alexander Leighton. from: Educational Review, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Nietzsche, sa Vie et sa Pensée: Les Precurseurs de Nietzsche 1920 by Charles Andler. from: The Journal of Philosophy, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Nietzsche, sa Vie et sa Pensée: Vol. II; La Jeunesse de Nietzsche jusqu' a la Rupture avec Bayreuth 1921 by Charles Andler. from: The Journal of Philosophy, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Nietzsche, sa Vie et sa Pensée. Vol. III; Le Pessimism Esthétique de Nietzsche, sa Philosophie à l'Epoque Wagnérienne 1921 by Charles Andler. from: The Journal of Philosophy, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Nietzsche, et le Transformisme Intellectualiste: la Philosophie de sa Période Francaise 1922 by Charles Andler. from: The Journal of Philosophy, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Planktonkunde 1910 and Leitfaden der Planktonkunde. by Dr. Adolph Steuer. from: Science, 1912 (Box 1)
  - Science and the Human Mind, a Critical and Historical Account of the Development of Natural Knowledge, 1912. by William Cecil Dampier Whetham. from: Science, 1913 (Box 1)